Guide to the Harry Weinberger Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
O'Day, Caroline -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Older, Fremont -- Goldman, Emma
O'Leary, Arthur T. -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
O'Leary, Jeremiah A. -- Troy, Lillian Scott
O'Neill, Eugene -- Provincetown Players
O'Neill, Harry F. -- Bales, William B.; Goldman, Emma; Kramer, Louis
Overstreet, Harry A. -- The God of Vengeance
Owens, Franklin -- Crumit, Frank
Palma, Raul -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Palmer, A. Mitchell -- Abrams, Jacob
Pan-American Federation of Labor -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Paul, Alice -- Abrams, Jacob
Paxton, Sidney -- Cape Playhouse Inc.
Pearlman, Nathan D. -- Vaccination
Pearson's Magazine -- Rasmussen, Rasmus; St. John, Vincent
Pennsylvania Committee for Political Prisoners -- St. John, Vincent
People's Council of America -- Kramer, Louis
Pepper, James W. -- Rivera, Librado
Perales, Pedro -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Perls, Edwin A. -- The God of Vengeance
Perls, L. T. -- The God of Vengeance
Peters, John A. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Philadelphia Bar Association -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Phillips, Nathaniel -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Pierce, Ralph S. -- Kaplunoff, Matthew
Pinchott, Amos -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Pinchot, Gifford -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial; Rangel, Jesus M.
Pollak, Walter -- The God of Vengeance
Pollock, Channing -- The God of Vengeance
Pollock, Frederick -- Abrams, Jacob
Powers, Mary -- Kreymborg, Alfred
Proletarian Party, O'Brien Defense Committee -- O'Brien, Charles M.
The Public -- Simpson, Samuel W.
Publishers' Weekly -- Kreymborg, Alfred
G. P. Putnam's Sons -- Purdy, Elias W.
Quinn, John -- The God of Vengeance
Ralston, Jackson H. -- Bosco, Paul; Mariani, Vito
Recht, Charles -- Abrams, Jacob; O'Brien, Charles M.
Reedy, William H. -- Goldman, Emma
Reichman, Emil H. -- Mosson, Isidore
Reinheimer, Howard E. -- Cheney, Sheldon
Reitman, Ben L. -- Becker, Morris; Eckardt, Harold; Goldman, Emma; Reitman, Ben L.
Rice, Elmer -- Collins, Delores L.; The God of Vengeance; Theatre Alliance Inc.
Rifkind, Albert J. -- Goldman, Emma
Rimer, Minnie -- Goldman, Emma
Robinson, D. Stuart -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Rogers, Edward S. -- Cheney, Sheldon
Romig, James E. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Roosevelt, Eleanor -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Roosevelt, Franklin D. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Rosalsky, Otto -- Simpson, Samuel W.
Rosansky, Hyman -- Abrams, Jacob
Rosen, Jack -- Abels, Samuel
Rosenberg, Arthur L. -- Goldman, Emma
Rosenberg, James N. -- The God of Vengeance
Ross, Arthur L. -- The God of Vengeance
Rotman, Louis -- Rotman, Sarah
Rubio, G. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Ryckman, J. H. -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Sabath, Adolph J. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Sabbotovsky, Boris -- Cape Playhouse Inc.
Sanchez, Andres A. -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Sanchez, Raymond -- Fernandez, Jose R.
Sanders, Everett -- Borghi, Armando
Santamaria, Placido -- Fernandez, Jose R.
Sarnoff, Lillie -- Flores Magon, Ricardo; Garcia, Manuel Rey; St. John, Vincent
Schildkraut, Joseph -- The God of Vengeance
Schroeder, Theodore -- The God of Vengeance; Goldman, Emma; Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Schulman, Samuel -- The God of Vengeance
Schwartz, Maurice -- Toller, Ernst
Schwebel, Max -- Selwyn and Co.
Seabury, Samuel -- The God of Vengeance; Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Secular Society of New York -- Meirowitz, Irving
Seldes, George S. -- Borghi, Armando
Selwyn and Co. -- The God of Vengeance
Shay, Felix -- Goldman, Emma
Sheppard, Morris -- Bergdoll, Grover C.; Rangel, Jesus M.
Sheridan, Clare -- St. John, Vincent
Sherburne, John H. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Sherwood, Robert -- Carruthers, Gloria
Shewalter, Joseph D. -- Goldman, Emma
Shipstead, Henrik -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Shorell, Herbert L. -- Carruthers, Gloria
Shorr, Isaac -- Berstein, Ethel; Parsons, Robert
Shortt, William A. -- Bingham, Richard E.
Shurr, Louis -- Crumit, Frank
Simon and Schuster -- Cheney, Sheldon
Sinclair, Upton -- Abrams, Jacob; Bergdoll, Grover C.; Bosco, Paul; Flores Magon, Ricardo; Goldman, Emma
Sirovich, William I. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.; Kreymborg, Alfred
Sladovich, George -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Sloan, Anna -- Goldman, Emma
Smith, Alfred E. -- The God of Vengeance
Smith, Augustus H. -- College Entrance Book Co.
Smith, Whitmel H. -- Bingham, Richard E.
Society to Lower Rents -- Simpson, Samuel W.
Sommer, Frank H. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Soto y Gama, Diaz -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Steffens, Lincoln -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Steimer, Mollie -- Abrams, Jacob
Stowe, L. Beecher -- Goldman, Emma
Stuhler, William R. -- Crumit, Frank
Studell, Harold -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Sugar, Maurice -- Becker, Maurice
Taft, Henry W. -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Taft, Robert A. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Taft, Harry A. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Teagle, C. A. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Tellez, Manuel C. -- Flores Magon, Ricardo; Rangel, Jesus M.; Rivera, Librado
Teltsch, Gus -- Flores Magon, Ricardo
Texas, State of -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Thomas, Norman -- Abrams, Jacob; Bergdoll, Grover C.
Throckmorten, Cleon -- Provincetown Players
Tobey, Charles W. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Todd, Helen -- Flores Magon, Ricardo; The God of Vengeance
Towne, Elizabeth -- Latson, William R. C.
Tresca, Carlo -- Goldman, Emma
Tumulty, Joseph P. -- Goldman, Emma
Turner, Albert -- Latson, William R. C.
Tweedy, Edna B. -- Cape Playhouse Inc.
U.S. Army -- Bergdoll, Grover C.; Goldman, Emma
U.S. Department of Justice –- Abrams, Jacob; Andreytchine, George; Bales, William B.; Becker, Morris; Bergdoll, Grover C.; Campeo, Tomaso; Cape Playhouse Inc.; Ciafalo, Andrea; Flores Magon, Ricardo; Goldman, Emma; Itzickson, Jacob; Kaplunoff, Matthew; Kramer, Louis; Newlander, Carl; Rasmussen, Rasmus; Rivera, Librado; St. John, Vincent; Soelter, Herman R.; Voss, Carl; Zogg, Nicholas S.
U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration -- Abrams, Jacob; Andreytchine, George; Aurin, Harry; Aziz, Demitri; Baron, Rose; Becker, Morris; Bergdoll, Grover C.; Bernstein, Ethel; Borghi, Armando; Bosco, Paul; Bottvinick, Edka; Chenenky, Lena; Ciafalo, Andrea; Daniel, David S.; Dorfman, Liebe; Feltman, Emile; Fernandez, Jose R.; Fernandez, Ramon; Flores Magon, Ricardo; Garcia, Mauel Rey; George, Anthony; Goldman, Emma; Hued, Alejandro; Itzickson, Jacob; Kaplunoff, Matthew; Klein, Joshua; Kramer, Louis; Mariani, Vito; Martinez, Thomas; Newlander, Carl; O'Brien, Charles M.; Orlick, David; Parsons, Robert; Pavlova, Pearl; Perruchon, Peter; Potash, Irving; Rasmussen, Rasmus; Rivera, Librado; Rotman, Sarah; St. John, Vincent; Schneiderman, Morris; Sernaker, Bernard; Shimuni, Petrus; Slivinski, Victor; Vik, George; Voss, Carl; Wu, Gray; Zumpano, Salvatore
U.S. Department of State -- Abrams, Jacob; Bergdoll, Grover C.; Goldman, Emma; O'Brien, Charles M.; Rasmussen, Rasmus; Rivera, Librado
U.S. Navy -- Goldman, Emma
U.S. Penitentiary, Atlanta, Georgia -- Becker, Morris; Goldman, Emma; Kramer, Louis
U.S. Penitentiary, Leavenworth, Kansas -- Flores Magon, Ricardo; Rivera, Librado
U.S. Supreme Court, Clerk -- Abrams, Jacob; Bales, William B.; Goldman, Emma; Kramer, Louis; Krispens, William
U.S. Treasury Department -- Becker, Morris; Cape Playhouse Inc.; Goldman, Emma
U.S. War Department -- Bergdoll, Grover C.; Buzzi, Alfredo; Collins, Delores L.; Feltman, Emile; Goldman, Emma
United Hebrew Trades -- Goldman, Emma
Untermyer, Samuel -- The God of Vengeance
Vanderveer, George -- Andreytchine, George
Van Doren, Carl -- The God of Vengeance
Van Vulkenberg, W. S. -- Goldman, Emma
Vasconcelos, Jose -- Flores Magon, Ricardo; Rangel, Jesus M.
Vasquez, Leonardo L. -- Rangel, Jesus M.
Vladeck, B. Charney -- The God of Vengeance
Vogel Music Co. -- Crumit, Frank
Vorhees, W. A. -- The God of Vengeance
Wadsworth, James W. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Wanger, John I. -- Collins, Delores L.
Wald, Lillian D. -- Abrams, Jacob
Walsh, Frank P. -- Goldman, Emma; Mooney, Tom
Watson, Thomas E. -- Bosco, Paul; Goldman, Emma; Rangel, Jesus M.; Watson, Thomas E.
Weigle, W. Harold -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Weinberger, Milton R. -- Group Theatre; New York Theatrical Press Agents
Weinberger, Rita -- Weinberger, Erwin and Rita
Welsh, F. Bernard -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Wharton, John F. -- Cape Playhouse Inc.
Wheeler, Burton K. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Whitman, Charles S. -- Goldman, Emma
Williams, Henry D. -- Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Wilson, Kenneth E. -- Cape Playhouse Inc.
Wilson, Woodrow -- Abrams, Jacob
Wiman, Dwight D. -- Crumit, Frank
Winchell, Walter -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Winterich, John T. -- Bergdoll, Grover C.
Wirin, A. L. -- Parsons, Robert
Wise, Stephen S. -- The God of Vengeance; Andrew Hamilton Memorial
Wolff, William A. -- Latson, William R. C.
Wood, Charles E. S. -- Goldman, Emma
Woolsey, John M. -- Kreymborg, Alfred; Stange, Hugh; Theatre Alliance Inc.
Workers' Defense Union -- Abrams, Jacob; Bosco, Paul; Feltman, Emile; Flores Magon, Ricardo; Itzickson, Jacob; Kaplunoff, Matthew; Krispens, William; Pavlova, Pearl; Perrone, Felipe; Perruchon, Peter; Potash, Irving; St. John, Vincent; Voss, Carl
Workers' Prison Relief Committee -- Flores Magon, Ricardo; St. John, Vincent
Wormser, I. Maurice -- The God of Vengeance
Yellenti, Nicholas -- Crumit, Frank
Young, Arthur -- The God of Vengeance
The American Mercury; Anarchism; Civil rights; Communism; Copyright; Emigration and immigration; Law; Radicalism; Socialism; World War, 1914-1918; Lawyers; Anarchists; Abbott, Leonard Dalton, 1878-1953; Asch, Sholem, 1880-1957; Baker, Newton Diehl, 1871-1937; Baker, Ray Stannard, 1870-1946; Baldwin, Roger N. (Roger Nash), 1884-1981; Bankhead, William Brockman, 1874-1940; Barkley, Alben William, 1877-1956; Barnes, Djuna, 1892-; Barton, Bruce, 1886-1967; Beck, James M. (James Montgomery), 1861-1936; Bergdoll, Grover Cleveland; Berger, Victor L., 1860-1929; Berkman, Alexander, 1870-1936; Black, William A.; Blackwell, Alice Stone, 1857-1950; Blossom, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), 1878-; Boni, Albert, 1892-1981; Borah, William Edgar, 1865-1940; Brandeis, Louis Dembitz, 1856-1941; Brisbane, Arthur, 1864-1936; Browder, Earl, 1891-1973; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947; Callahan, James D.; Calles, Plutarco Elías, 1877-1945; Capper, Arthur, 1865-1951; Castleton, Samuel M.; Celler, Emanuel, 1888-1981; Cerf, Bennett, 1898-1971; Chafee, Zechariah, Jr., 1885-1957; Clark, Barrett H. (Barrett Harper), 1890-1953; Colcord, Lincoln, 1883-1947; Cook, George Cram, 1873-1924; Crane, Frank, 1861-1928; Creel, George, 1876-1953; Crumit, Frank; Dalzell, George W. (George Walton), 1877-1953; Dana, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, 1881-1950; Danziger, Samuel; Darrow, Clarence, 1857-1938; Daugherty, H. M. (Harry Micajah), 1860-1941; Davis, John W. (John William), 1873-1955; De Casseres, Benjamin, 1873-1945; Debs, Eugene V. (Eugene Victor), 1855-1926; DeSilver, Albert, 1888-1924; Deutsch, Bernard S. (Bernard Seymour), 1884-1935; Dodge, Wendell Phillips, 1883-; Downey, Sheridan, 1884-1961; Durante, Jimmy, 1893-1980; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969; Ernst, Morris L. (Morris Leopold), 1888-1976; Fadiman, Clifton, 1904-1999; Ferguson, Miriam Amanda, 1875-1961; Fish, Hamilton, 1888-1991; Fitzgerald, M. Eleanor (Mary Eleanor), 1877-1955; Flores Magón, Ricardo, 1873-1922; Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley; France, Joseph Irwin, 1873-1939; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965; Garner, John Nance, 1868-1967; Gilbert, Cass, 1859-1934; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940; Gompers, Samuel, 1850-1924; Grant, Percy Stickney, 1860-1927; Guffey, Joseph F., 1870-1959; Hand, Learned, 1872-1961; Hapgood, Norman, 1868-1937; Harding, Warren G. (Warren Gamaliel), 1865-1923; Harris, Frank, 1856-1931; Hickok, Guy C., 1888-1951; Hiss, Alger, 1904-1996; Holmes, John Haynes, 1879-1964; Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar), 1895-1972; Huntington, Henry Strong, 1836-1920; Hurst, Fannie, 1889-1968; Hylan, John Francis, 1868-1936; Jaffe, Sam, 1901-; Johnson, Hiram, 1866-1945; Johnson, Royal C. (Royal Cleaves), 1882-1939; Jones, J. Gordon; Kahn, Otto H., 1867-1934; Kiefer, Daniel, 1856-1923; Kreymborg, Alfred, 1883-1966; La Follette, Robert M. (Robert Marion), 1855-1925; La Follette, Robert M. (Robert Marion), 1895-1953; La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947; Lodge, Henry Cabot, Jr., 1902-1985; London, Meyer, 1871-1926; Markham, Edwin, 1852-1940; Marshall, Louis, 1856-1929; Mead, James M. (James Michael), 1885-1964; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956; Mielziner, Jo, 1901-1976; Minor, Robert, 1884-1952; Mooney, Thomas J., 1882-1942; Murphy, Frank, 1890-1949; Nathanson, Wm. (William), 1883-1963; Nearing, Scott, 1883-1983; Neff, Pat Morris, 1871-1952; Norris, George W. (George William), 1861-1944; Nye, Gerald P. (Gerald Prentice), 1892-1971; Obregón, Álvaro, 1880-1928; O'Day, Caroline, 1875-1943; Older, Fremont, 1856-1935; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953; Overstreet, H. A. (Harry Allen), 1875-1970; Palmer, A. Mitchell (Alexander Mitchell), 1872-1936; Pinchot, Amos, 1873-1944; Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946; Pollock, Channing, 1880-1946; Pollock, Frederick, 1845-1937; Post, Louis F. (Louis Freeland), 1849-1928; Reitman, Ben L. (Ben Lewis), 1879-1942; Rice, Elmer, 1892-1967; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945; Sabath, Adolph Joachim, 1866-1952; Schildkraut, Joseph, 1895-1964; Seabury, Samuel, 1873-1958; Seldes, George, 1890-1995; Sheppard, Morris, 1875-1941; Sherwood, Robert E. (Robert Emmet), 1896-1955; Shipstead, Henrik, 1881-1960; Shorr, Isaac, 1884-1964; Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968; Smith, Alfred Emanuel, 1873-1944; Stange, Hugh Stanislaus; Steffens, Lincoln, 1866-1936; Stowe, Lyman Beecher, 1880-1963; Taft, Robert A. (Robert Alphonso), 1889-1953; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968; Toller, Ernst, 1893-1939; Tresca, Carlo, 1879-1943; Tumulty, Joseph P. (Joseph Patrick), 1879-1954; Untermyer, Samuel, 1858-1940; Van Doren, Carl, 1885-1950; Voss, Carl Hermann, 1910-; Wald, Lillian D., 1867-1940; Walsh, Frank P.; Watson, Thomas E. (Thomas Edward), 1856-1922; Weinberger, Harry, 1888-; Wheeler, Burton K. (Burton Kendall), 1882-1975; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924; Winchell, Walter, 1897-1972; Winterich, John T., 1891-1970; Wise, Stephen S. (Stephen Samuel), 1874-1949; Young, Art, 1866-1943; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; American Civil Liberties Union; American Federation of Labor; American Fund for Public Service; League for the Amnesty of Political Prisoners; National Civil Liberties Bureau (U.S.)
- Original accession, 1915-1943
  - Abels, Samuel
    Scope and Contents
    The papers consist of letters and legal papers concerning New York vs. Samuel Abels, 1917. Abels was arrested, tried, and convicted for desecration of the flag. Weinberger appealed the conviction to the New York Supreme Court, alleging there was no violation of law, merely an expression of opinion. The lower court ruling was affirmed.
    - Correspondence
      - Abels, Samuel (13), 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Rosen, Jack (1), 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Legal papers, 1917 April-December (Box 1, Folder 2-7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Abrams, Jacob
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous papers concerning the cases: United States vs. Jacob Abrams et al., United States vs. Gabriel Prober et al., and Jacob Abrams et al. vs. United States, 1918-1921.
    Jacob Abrams, Hyman Lachowsky, Samuel Lipman, Gabriel Prober, Hyman Rosansky, Jacob Schwartz, and Mollie Steimer were admitted anarchists charged with violating the wartime Espionage Act. The defendents had distributed pamphlets denouncing American intervention in Russia in 1918 as contrary to the best interests of the Russian people. Prober, Schwartz, and Rosansky were dropped from the case, leaving the "Four Russians - Jacob Abrams, Hyman Lachowsky, Samuel Lipman, and Mollie Steimer. Weinberger was attorney for the accused, and after their conviction in 1918, he unsuccessfully sought to obtain executive clemency. The "Four Russians" were deported to the USSR in 1923. Interest in this case was widespread, due in large part to Weinberger's efforts in publicizing the impact of the trial and the convictions on the civil liberties of the individual. This section includes letters from many prominent Americans expressing their opinions on this case.
    - Correspondence
      - A-W, Y (220), 1918-1921, undated (Box 1, Folder 9-16)
      - Abbott, Leonard D. (5), 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Abrams, Jacob (83), 1918-1921, undated (Box 1, Folder 18-20)
      - Abrams, Mrs. Jacob (4), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Abrams, Lachowsky, Lipman, and Steimer (regarding imprisonment and trials) (84), 1918-1921 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - American Federation of Labor (4), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - American Freedom Foundation (4), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Baker, Newton D. (1), 1918 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Baker, Ray Stannard (10), 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Ballentine, Stella (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Bernstein, Rose (11), 1920, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Blossom, Frederick (7), 1918-1920 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Brandeis, Louis D. (2), 1918, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Brisbane, Arthur (3), 1918, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Castleton, Samuel M. (5), 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Chafee, Zachariah (12), 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Citizen's Amnesty Committee (4), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Cohn, Michael A. (13), 1918-1921 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Colcord, Lincoln (2), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Creed, George (10), 1918, 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Dana, H. W. L. (3), 1920 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Daugherty, Harry M.
        General note
        See: U.S. Department of Justice, Attorney General, box 2, folders 12-13
      - Debs, Eugene V. (1), 1921 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - DeSilver, Albert (10), 1919-1921 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Durkee, Harris S. (9), 1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Flynn, Elizabeth G.
        See: Workers' Defense Union, box 2, folder 20
      - France, Joseph I. (5), 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Frankfurter, Felix (3), 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Hapgood, Norman (6), 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Inglis, Agnes (6), 1919-1921 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Kiefer, Daniel (5), 1919-1921 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - King, Alexander
        See: U.S. Department of Justice, Solicitor General, box 2, folder 15
      - Kovner, Hilda (7), 1920-1921 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Lachowsky, Hyman (17), 1918-1921 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - LaFollette, Robert M. (6), 1918-1921 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - LaGuardia, Fiorello H. (3), 1920 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Lewisohn, Alice and Irene (5), 1918-1920 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Lipman, Samuel (35), 1919-1921 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Missouri State Prisons
        See: Abrams, Lachowsky, Lipman, and Steimer, box 1, folder 21
      - The Nation (5), 1918, 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Nearing, Scott (1), 1921 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Mitchell, Palmer A.
      - Paul, Alice (1), 1921 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Pollock, Frederick (1), 1921 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Recht, Charles (19), 1919-1923 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Rosansky, Mr. and Mrs. Hyman (8), 1918-1919 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Sinclair, Upton (4), 1918-1920 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Steimer, Mollie (61), 1918-1922, undated (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
      - Thomas, Norman (2), 1919 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - U.S. Department of Justice, Attorney General (61), 1919-1921 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
      - U.S. Department of Justice, Pardon Attorney (23), 1918-1921 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - U.S. Department of Justice, Solicitor General (41), 1918-1919 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - U.S. Department of Justice, U.S. Attorney, New Orleans (9), 1919 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - U.S. Department of Justice, U.S. Attorney, New York (39), 1918-1920 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (109), 1919-1921 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
      - U.S. Department of State (2), 1921 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - U.S. Penitentiary, Atlanta, Georgia
      - U.S. Supreme Court, Clerk (33), 1918-1919 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Wald, Lillian D. (5), 1918-1921 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Wilson, Woodrow (31), 1920-1921 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Workers' Defense Union (6), 1919-1921, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Legal papers
      - 1918 April-December (Box 2, Folder 21-26)
      - 1919-1921, undated (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
      - Lachowsky, Hyman, 1919, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Steimer, Molly, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    - Notes (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - American Legal Defense League, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    The League was interested in cases concerning civil liberties and rights in wartime. This section contains notes and opinions by Weinberger, council for the League, on the cases of Loewe DeBoer, George L. Glison, Henry Jager, and Joseph Sadokierski. More material on these four cases is filed separately under the individual names.
  - Andreyeff, Wasily
    The papers consist of correspondence. Weinberger arranged bond for actor Andreyeff who was being held for deportation. Andreyeff was deported to Russia in 1921.
    - Andreyeff, Wasily (7), 1918-1919, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Cohn, Michael A. (1), 1921 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (8), 1920-1921 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Andreytchine, George
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous concerning United States vs. George Andreytchine, 1919-1923. Weinberger acted as attorney for Andreytchine, a member of the International Workers of the World (I. W. W.), and obtained his release on $10,000 bail. Andreytchine disappeared and the bail was forfeited in 1922.
    - Correspondence
      - C, D, H, I, N, P (9), 1919, 1921, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Andreytchine, Mr. and Mrs. George (20), 1919 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Berman, Morris (13), 1921-1923 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Christensen, Otto (28), 1919, 1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Eastman, Max (9), 1921-1922 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - General Defense Committee (13), 1921-1922 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - U.S. Department of Justice (13), 1919 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (4), 1919 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Legal papers, 1919, 1921 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Ashleigh, Charles
    See: St. John, Vincent, box 45, folder 6 See: St. John, Vincent, box 46, folder 2
  - Aurin, Harry
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, and miscellaneous papers concerning New York vs. Harry Aurin, 1917. Weinberger defended Aurin who was charged with disorderly conduct and the distribution of illegal handbills. The handbills contained excerpts from the Declaration of Independence.
    - Correspondence: Aurin, Harry (15) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Legal papers, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Notes (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Aziz, Demitri
    The papers consist of letters and legal papers. Weinberger acted as attorney for deportees Demitri Aziz, Rosa Orodovsky, and Jacob Goodman.
    - Correspondence
      - Aziz, Demitri (2), 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Darrow, Sisman, and Popham (2), 1919 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - U.S. Department of Labor, Immigration (6), 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Legal papers, 1919 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Baldazzi, Giovanni
    See: St. John, Vincent, box 45, folder 7
  - Bales, William B.
    Scope and Contents note
    The papers consist of letters, legal papers, notes, clippings, and miscellaneous papers concerning United States vs. W. B. Bales, 1917 (United States District Court, New York), and United States vs. W. B. Bales, 1918 (United States Supreme Court). William B. Bales was arrested on a charge of failing to register for the draft and released on bail. The case was dismissed and Bales was ordered to perform non-combatant duty. The bail money was ordered returned less 1% for clerk's fees. Weinberger successfully appealed to the United States Supreme Court on the grounds that the deduction was unconstitutional.